# Shahid Shaikh

#### **Shahid Shaikh**

Email: shahid@codeforgeek.com

Phone: 9768820285

Website: https://codeforgeek.com

#### **Skills**

Currently working as a Technology architect in Accion labs Pvt ltd. In the past, he has worked as a senior engineer in Zebpay Services Pvt Ltd, India's biggest cryptocurrency exchange. He holds more than 5 years of professional experience in the industry.

He has worked extensively on Node.js ecosystem and developed applications that are running in production. He is Expert in Backend application development (Using Node ecosystem). Blockchain, Decentralized Applications, and Microservices architecture. He has worked extensively on complex projects with Microservices architecture applications and has hands on in serverless applications using AWS Lambda. He has working experience with MySQL,MariaDB, MongoDB, Redis, ElasticSearch, PostgreSQL and hands on experience with DynamoDB, Cassandra, Hive. He has worked with RabbitMQ and Kafka as Message queues. He has also working experience with infrastructures such as Amazon, Azure, and customers of Digitalocean.

He is Published author of **three** books and founder of a programming tutorial site with **1**+ **million** views a month.

### **Experience**

# Accion Labs Pvt ltd | Technology Architect

Feb 2018-PRESENT

Currently working on to develop one of it's kind IOT based decentralized network to facilitate villages/remote areas with digital technology.

**Technologies**: IPFS, OrbitDB, BatmanADV, RaspberryPI with sensors, Node.js, Python

### ZebPay Service Ptd Ltd | Senior Engineer

April 2018 - FEB 2019

Zebpay is India's biggest cryptocurrency exchange. I am working on the blockchain part as a senior engineer.

## Accion technologies Pvt ltd | Technology lead

June 2014- December 2017

American water (May 2017- DECEMBER 2017)

Successfully leading a team of 5 people to develop and deploy **microservices-based backend applications** to support various components in one portal. Components vary from

content extraction from **Liferay**, chatbots to read and reply to emails and global search with a recommendation.

OODEBE (October 2016- PRESENT)

Successfully developed the product called **OODEBE** (Object-oriented data exploration and binding engine) to perform the polyglot persistence across various heterogeneous databases. Developed it as a framework to support open source contributions easily.

Insurance Assist(January 2016- October 2016)

Successfully lead the backend team to develop scalable and easy to manage the system for one of the India's largest insurance providers. Developed and deployed the microservices-based backend application.

Project website: <a href="https://eb.globalinsurance.co.in">https://eb.globalinsurance.co.in</a>

UVA Mobile (August 2015- December 2016)

Worked as a backend developer and integration lead in the **UVA Mobile** project. Developed modules to integrate the communication system in the telecom sector.

#### **Projects**

Spark (https://spark.shellstack.com)

It is content extraction and sharing product which is SaaS based.

Code for Geek (https://codeforgeek.com)

It is Programming tutorial website to teach web technologies such as Node.js, Angular, databases, etc

# Authored Books

#### Sails.js essentials

(https://www.packtpub.com/web-development/sailsjs-essentials).

Mastering rethinkdb

(https://www.packtpub.com/big-data-and-business-intelligence/mastering-rethinkdb)

**Learning Azure Cosmos DB** 

https://www.packtpub.com/in/big-data-and-business-intelligence/learning-azure-cosmos-db

Education

June 2010 - June 2014, Mumbai

He has completed B.E(CS) from MH Saboo Siddik College of Engineering with Distinction.